#### Sean Brown 11012 N 147<sup>th</sup> E Ave Owasso, OK 74055 Email scbrown1986@gmail.com

## **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

MBA with nine years technical experience, holding positions in Design, Sustaining, and Industrial Engineering. Demonstrated software development, project management and leadership skills. Proven ability to problem solve when faced with complex and conflicting data and priorities and to handle multiple projects at one time. Extensive process improvement and quality improvement experience. Successfully work across multi-functional areas and within cost and schedule constraints to meet company mission and objectives.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Senior Engineer**, The Nordam Group, Transparency Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma January 2016-Present, Full Time, Salaried

Developed a manufacturing planning workflow application that facilitates coordination between Manufacturing Engineering, Production, Quality, and Engineering to ensure that manufacturing instructions meet strict engineering data requirements.

Project Engineer on New Product Implementation (NPI) opportunities. Role included product and process design, research and development of design and manufacturing solutions, risk analysis, product and business process improvement, project scheduling and budget, customer consultation, and root cause and corrective action management.

Led lessons learned and process improvement exercises to diagnose process inefficiencies, determine and develop operational best practices. Gathered data and insight from multiple sources to inform teams and management of key performance indicators and process control effectiveness. Developed process improvement solutions that reduced labor and material costs for several product lines by up to 88%.

Technical subject matter expert (SME) for internal customers, which included providing labor, material, and overall finance analysis and forecasting, writing technical proposals, and determining manufacturing feasibility, including capital expenditure and capacity requirements.

**Engineer II**, The Nordam Group, Transparency Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma November 2011 – January 2016, Full Time, Salaried

Visited technology partners to identify, review, and assess solution options. Examples include collaborating with a vision system supplier to automate transparent material inspection, reducing inspection time from 1 hour to 30 seconds, and incorporating barcode and inkjet technology into a part identification process to reduce process time from 5 minutes to 15 seconds and eliminate serial number errors.

Programmed and led implementation of an innovative material certification database to meet a need for complete visibility and traceability of material data. Database manages FAA-audited material certification data, maintains complete material traceability from raw stock material to finished product, and incorporates a material testing module for calculating material properties from Quality lab test outputs. Database has proven 100% effective preventing non-certified material from being released to Production for use in aircraft components.

Prioritized clear written communication to provide senior level reporting, showing process trends and highlighting risk indicators affecting project success. Acted as subject matter expert to lead the ideation and technical development of new products.

**Industrial Engineer II**, The Nordam Group, Transparency Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma October 2010 – November 2011, Full Time, Salaried

Lead for process improvement implementation projects that have resulted in innovation and changes to well-established manufacturing processes. Devised a new method of forming aircraft cabin windows resulting in a 10% throughput increase with a 75% reduction in equipment footprint, an innovative

**Engineer I**, The Nordam Group, Interiors and Structures Division, Tulsa, Oklahoma June 2008 – October 2010, Full Time, Salaried

Visited and coordinated with customers, including Hawker Beechcraft, Learjet, Bombardier Completions Center Montreal, and Gulfstream, in dual engineering and estimating roles to support existing programs, procure new business, and develop solutions to customer requirements.

# **SKILLS**

Software and Web Development

- Visual Basic
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- PHP
- WordPress
- Twitter Bootstrap
- jQuery
- GitHub

Technical Leadership

 Proven ability to refine operational and technical requirements, diagnose process issues, and develop innovative solutions for internal and external customers

Project Management

Mentorship

**Process Improvement** 

Quality Improvement

Relational Databases and ERPs (Microsoft Access, SQL, SAP)

Database Management

**Technical Writing** 

• Extensive experience documenting processes and reporting project data and solutions

Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis

 Performed data gathering and qualitative analysis for process improvement initiatives. Utilized statistical analysis software, such as Minitab and Excel, to evaluate business theories and make informed process design decisions

Microsoft Products (Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, MS Project, Outlook, SharePoint, Visio)

### **EDUCATION**

**B.S.** Aerospace Engineering **B.S.** Mechanical Engineering

2008

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma

Overall GPA 3.48

**Masters of Business Administration (MBA)** 

2016

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, Oklahoma

**GPA 4.00**